<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Adam Hartleb</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Adam Hartleb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-cn</language>
    <copyright>©2020 Adam Hartleb.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 10:48:11 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Rust - Hello World</title>
      <link>/post/intro-to-rust-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 10:48:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/intro-to-rust-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Installing and configuring Rust is a breeze with rustup which is an installer for Rust. You can download it by visiting:
https://rustup.rs/
And following the onscreen instructions. You can confirm that the installation has worked by running:
rustc --version The rustup installation also comes with another command line tool called cargo which is the Rust packager manager &amp;ndash; akin to npm for Node. Rust packages are called crates and there is an online repository of crates visible here:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Typescript - Getting Started</title>
      <link>/post/intro-to-typescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 10:48:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/intro-to-typescript/</guid>
      <description>What is TypeScript? TypeScript is a transpile-to-JavaScript language meaning that a program written in Typescript must first be translated (transpiled) to JavaScript before it can be run in the browser. Although compiling typically has a different meaning, the TypeScript community refers to this process as compilation. Why would anyone want to go through this process though? Because TypeScript comes with a host of features on top of those already available in JavaScript, all aimed at making writing JavaScript code more robust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Object Oriented Programming</title>
      <link>/post/intro-to-oop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 15:07:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/intro-to-oop/</guid>
      <description>Introduction What exactly is an object? An object is defined by two components: properties and behaviors. A car has properties like its color, the year it was made, if it&amp;rsquo;s 4WD or not, etc. It also has behaviors such as starting, driving and so on. Having both of these components is key because if you just have behaviors then you&amp;rsquo;re simply dealing with functions that transform their inputs and return the output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Structs</title>
      <link>/post/cs-structs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cs-structs/</guid>
      <description>Structs and Classes are constructed very similarly in C#:
struct Book { private string title; private int[] editions; public string Title { get { return title; } set { title = value; } } public string Author { get; set; } public int[] Editions { get { return editions; } set { editions = value; } } public string Blurb() { return $&amp;quot;{Title} by {Author}&amp;quot;; } } And they are instantiated in the same way:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Autoimplemented Properties</title>
      <link>/post/cs-autoimplemented-props/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cs-autoimplemented-props/</guid>
      <description>In object-oriented programming, you&amp;rsquo;ll often be creating getters and setters for instance variables. For example:
class Book { private string title; public Book(string title) { this.title = title; } GetTitle() { return title; } SetTitle(string title) { this.title = title; } } The problem with this is that it&amp;rsquo;s verbose and creating getters and setters is extremely common so it becomes a little cumbersome. Now, you might be thinking &amp;ldquo;If I can just freely get and set the instance variable, why not make its accessibility public?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Reference</title>
      <link>/post/markdown-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/markdown-example/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>